A. D. Bache Collection 1833-1873 Mss.B.B123
American Philosophical Society
- LS to the Committee on the Central High School of Philadelphia, 1858 November 25; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Washington, D.C. Letter of recommendation for George Schaffer (?) to fill the position of principal.
- ALS to William Henry Seward, 1859 March 7; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Requesting Seward's assistance in obtaining a cadet spot for Edmund A. Blunt, whose father worked for the Coast Survey.
- LS to Isaac Toucey, 1859 March 21; 2pp.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Washington, D.C. Letter to the Secretary of the Navy recommending Prof. George C. Schaeffer for the chair of Natural and Experimental Philosophy at the U.S. Naval School in Annapolis.
- LS. to Charles B. Clavert, 1859 July 16; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Near Machias, ME. Letter of recommendation for George C. Schaeffer.
- ALS to T. Apoleon Cheney, 1859 July 29; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Near Machias, Me. Reply to Cheney's request for maps and charts.
- LS to T. Apoleon Cheney, 1859 September 8; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Coast Survey Station, near Lane's Brook, Me. Is sending Cheney maps and charts requested, comments on his duty on the Lighthouse Board.
- LS to T. Apoleon Cheney, 1859 September 9; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Coast Survey Station, near Lane's Brook, Me. Thanks him for the publications sent.
- ALS to Thomas W. Olcutt, 1859 November 18; 3pp.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Philadelphia, PA. Recounts the events of his meeting with Dr. Peters and Prof. Pericu (?) at Cambridge.
- LS to Tench Tilghman, 1860 January 12; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Coast Survey Office. Invitiation to the members of the United States Agricultural Society to visit the Coast Survey Office.
- ALS to W. P. Fessenden, 1860 May 8; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Coast Survey Office. Regarding the application of Mr. H. W.Longfellow.
- ALS to Lambert Quetelet, 1860 May 22; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Washington, D.C. Letter of introduction for P. Peirce of Harvard while in Europe.
- ALS to W. P. Fessenden, 1860 July 20; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Gunstock Mt. near Laconia, N.H. Regarding a summer position for Mr. Longfellow. Comments on Fessenden's ability to join him during the summer.
- ALS to J. M. Schofield, 1860 September 24; 3pp.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Wachusett Mt., Fitchburg MA. Bache's recommendation to Schofield on accepting the observatory.
- LS to T. Apoleon Cheney, 1860 October 12; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  C.S. Station near Fitchburg, MA. Has sent list of maps in the Coast Survey office.
- ALS to Charles A. Spencer, 1861 May 25; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Washington, D.C. Bache will comply with Spencer's request.
- ALS to unidentified correspondent, 1861 June 2; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
- ALS to George C. Schaeffer, 1861 December 20; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Regarding Professor Gillespie of Union College visiting.
- ALS to William P. Fessenden, 1862 January 18; 2pp.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Coast Survey Office. Regarding no. 154 supported by Mr. Sherman.
- ALS to T. Apoleon Cheney, 1862 May 1; 2pp.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Coast Survey Office. Regarding publications.
- ALS to George W. Childs, 1862 October 15; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Philadelphia, PA. Has forwarded the matter to the office.
- LS to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1863 January 3; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Coast Survey Office. Regarding Mr. Mechan as a guide, and sending the requested material.
- LS to W. L. Nicholson, 1863 May 1; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Coast Survey Office. Regarding Nicholson's appointment as Topographer to the Post Office Department.
- ALS to Alexander Dallas Bache, 1864 May 21; 3pp.; Hale, Charles (Box 1)
  Washington, D.C. Consul-general of the U.S. to Egypt, requesting maps and documents of the war be sent to him.
- ALS to Alexander Dallas Bache, 1864 November 4; 3pp.; Brewster, Sir David (Box 1)
  Melrose. Thanks Bache for the Lighthouse Board reports, is sending pamphlet of his on dioptric lighthouses. Is interested how they are viewed in the United States as the matter is under review in England.
- ALS to Theron C. Terwilliger, 1873 January 10; 1p.; Bache, Albert Dabadie, 1832-1895 (Box 1)
  Philadelphia, PA. Death of his uncle and father-in-law.
- ALS to S. B. Ruggles, March 4; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Regarding Gen. Fisk.
- ALS to unidentified correspondent, March 7; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Regarding visit to see Mrs. Dobbin (?).
- ALS to Prof. Frisinani, June 12; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Photocopy of original in Diederich Collection 138 g University of Amsterdame Library.
- ALS to Alexander Dallas Bache, July 22; 2pp.; Paine, R. T. (Box 1)
  Woods Hole, MA. Unable to see Bache at Indian Hill, possible future meeting. Mr. Everett's speech at the British Association.
- ALS to George C. Schaeffer, December 7; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Date for next meeting.
- ALS to A. Campbell, December 27; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Coast Survey Office. Regarding a printing.
- ALS to Charles Coquerel, Monday evening; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Regarding a request.
- ALS to Mr. Gibbons, Tuesday; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Regarding the taking of water temperature.
- ALS to Charles Coquerel, Wednesday; 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Regarding Bache's visit while in Paris.
- ANS to unidentified correspondent, 1p.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 1)
  Small note regarding the "Department."